Joan Lazo Morales

Lima, Perú (GMT-5) (+51) 997-971032 <u>joanlazomorales@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/joan-lazo-morales

Front-end developer with 2 years of experience developing applications in the banking and e-commerce sector, oriented to good practices and defect monitoring; Currently, I am interested in entering the QA area, so I am developing skills as a Tester, one of my short-term goals is to become an automated Tester. I consider myself passionate about self-learning, observant, analytical, flexible, and oriented to teamwork.

EXPERIENCE

Interfondos, Peru - Web Application Development and UI / UX (January 2020 - Present)

- Developed new operations for the Erni website, allowing users to carry out transfers, opening, subscription, and redemptions online, achieved a 70% increase in new users, exceeding the annual goal of 2020.
- Developed and implemented the Erni Business applications, which allowed entering a new user profile oriented to companies, which increased the percentage of users to 10%.
- Implemented SEO tools, applying good practices and tools such as Hotjar, Google Tag Manager, and Analytics, allowing to know the possible indecencies of the users by 20%.
- Executed functional tests in the UAT phase, preventing failures by 70%, making reports to correct them, as well as reports for the back-end.
- Validated the design for web and mobile applications, ensuring usability and correct operation principles adapted to the tools used in the project.

Tech-Stack: TypeScript, Angular 6, jQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJS, SQL Server, .NET, C#, HTML, Sass, CSS, manual Tests.

Klick It, Peru - Front-end Developer (July 2019 - December 2019)

- Developed the responsive design adapted to the client, working under Agile Methodologies (Scrum and Kanban), achieving the fulfillment of virtual stores' delivery and development objectives developed in Magento e-commerce.
- Executed functional tests based on the end-user in the UAT phase, preventing failures by 40%, making reports and documentation to my team.
- Generated the documentation by template type in GitLab, leaving a history of use for future development, supporting my team.

Tech-Stack: JavaScript, Magento, ¡Query, Bootstrap, SQL, PHP, HTML, Less, CSS, manual Tests.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: (Familiar): JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, Typescript, Node, SQL.

Frameworks and Tools: Postman, Jest, Katalon Studio, Angular, React, API Rest, Figma, Zeplin, Bootstrap, Firebase, jQuery, Bitbucket, Jira, Hotjar, Google Tag Manager, ng2-google-recaptcha, Chart.js.

Languages: English, Basic; Spanish, Native.

EDUCATION

Laboratoria – Peru, Lima

Front-end application developer, November 2018 - April 2019

National University of Education Enrique Guzman y Valle - Peru, Lima

Bachelor of Education Sciences, E-learning specialist, January 2011 - December 2015

CERTIFICATES

Test Automation with Katalon Studio, Udemy, July 2021

I International Bootcamp in Services and Digital Innovation, Presidency of the Council of Ministers, May 2021

Certification Scrum fundamentals, Scrum Study, February 2021

Hackathon, Hacking inequality, Laboratoria, October 2020